荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   麻绳力攻
翻译   波隆史铎克渥斯
翻译   Rubilacxe
君临 King's Landing
翻译   北落师门
红堡
Red Keep
校对   泰温公爵
校对   Barossa
龙石岛
Dragonstone
时间轴   poplar
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
临冬城
Winterfell
后期    Jeremy
监制    临冬城的狮子   托曼
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第五集  The First of His Name
托曼一世
愿战士赐予他勇气
May the Warrior grant him courage
佑他穿越艰险
and protect him in these perilous times.
愿铁匠赐予他力量
May the Smith grant him strength
助他肩负重任
that he might bear this heavy burden
愿老妪
And may the Crone,
愿知晓所有人命运的老妪
she that knows the fate of all men,
指明他的必经之路
show him the path he must walk
引领他穿过前方的黑暗
and guide him through the dark places that lie ahead.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”  御林铁卫队长
在七神的光辉之下 我宣布
In the light of the Seven, I now proclaim Tommen
拜拉席恩家族的托曼一世
of the House Baratheon First of His Name
大主教
七神的代言人
为安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men
和七大王国的的统治者
and Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
愿他江山永固！
Long may he reign!
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
托曼·拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
玛格丽·提利尔
乔佛里·拜拉席恩的遗孀
托曼·拜拉席恩的未婚妻
真是特别的一天
Special day.
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
派席尔
大学士
陛下
Your Grace.
- 陛下  - 陛下
- Your Grace. - Your Grace.
陛下
Your Grace.
他就在那儿
There he is.
愿他江山永固
Long may he reign.
他坐在王座上 就像天生的王者
He sits the throne like he was born to it.
对 但他曾经不是
Yes. He wasn't, though, was he?
确实
No, he wasn't.
你还在为乔佛里哀悼吗？
You still mourn for Joffrey?
他曾是我的丈夫 我的国王
He was my husband. My king.
他本会成为你的噩梦
He would have been your nightmare.
陛下 我觉得——
Your Grace, I feel--
你很清楚他是什么样的人
You knew exactly what he was.
我也知道
I did, too.
没有任何感情可以代替
You never love anything in the world
你对自己第一个孩子的爱
the way you love your first child.
无论他们做了什么
Doesn't matter what they do.
其实他的所作所为让我震惊
And what he did, it shocked me.
你觉得我是会被轻易震惊的人吗？
Do you think I'm easily shocked?
不是
No.
但我真的被他的行为震惊了
The things he did shocked me.
他只是个孩子
He's only a boy.
一个心地善良 品行端正的孩子
A good boy. A decent boy.
一直都是
He always has been.
我在想 上一个品行端正的国王是谁？
Who was the last decent king, I wonder?
他会成为近五十年来第一个
He could be the first man who sits on that throne
真正有资格坐在王座上的国王
in 50 years to actually deserve it.
相对于把他推上王位的那场灾祸
It would be some consolation, wouldn't it?
这也算是一种安慰了 不是吗？
For all the horror that put him there.
如果他想统治好……
He will need help...
就需要别人的帮助
if he's going to rule well.
你可以帮他
He has you.
仅有母亲是不够的
A mother is not enough.
你仍想当王后 是吗？
You're still interested in being queen, I take it?
经历了这么多之后——
After all that's happened--
我知道这听起来很奇怪，但我——
it sounds strange, I know, but I am--
我还从来没有考虑过
I haven't even given any thought to it,
接下来要做什么
what comes next.
当然 这将会是无上的荣誉
It would be a great honor, of course.
但我需要和我父亲商量一下
But I will have to speak to my father about it.
是啊 和你的父亲商量一下吧
Yes, speak to your father.
我也会和我父亲商量
I'll speak to mine.
接下来 怕是要有一连串的婚礼等着咱们了
We may be faced with an alarming number of weddings soon.
我都不知道该称呼您什么好
I won't even know what to call you.
嫂子？
Sister?
还是母亲？
Or Mother?
乔佛里·拜拉席恩国王死了
King Joffrey Baratheon is dead.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
在他自己的婚礼上被谋杀
Murdered at his own wedding.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
另外我们已经控制了弥林的海军 陛下
And we have taken the Meereenese navy, Your Grace.
次子团接管了弥林海军
The Second Sons took the Meereenese navy.
谁允许你这么做的？
Who told you to take the navy?
没人
No one.
那你为什么要这样做？
So why did you do it?
我听说您喜欢船
I heard you liked ships.
达里奥·纳哈里斯
前次子团团长
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
女王铁卫 “无畏的”
有多少艘船
How many ships?
九十三艘 陛下
93, Your Grace.
能载多少人？
How many men can they carry?
不算水手的话 九千三百人
9,300, not counting sailors.
要攻下君临 这些人够么？
Would that be enough to take King's Landing?
兰尼斯特的兵力更多
The Lannisters have more.
他们已为乔佛里征战多年
They've been fighting Joffrey's wars for years.
疲惫不堪 而且兵力分散
They're tired, dispersed.
如今国王已死
And now their king is dead.
八千无垢者 两千次子团
8,000 Unsullied, 2,000 Second Sons
驶入黑水湾中
sailing into Blackwater Bay
可以迅雷之势突破城门
and storming the gates without warning.
很难说 也许人数是够了
It's hard to say. It could be enough.
但我们并非要让您只成为君临的女王
But we're not fighting to make you queen of King's Landing.
而一万人可征服不了整个维斯特洛
10,000 men can't conquer Westeros.
一旦女王渡过狭海
The old houses will flock to our queen
那些古老的家族都将蜂拥至女王旗下
when she crosses the Narrow Sea.
那些家族都是些墙头草 只会拥护胜者
The old houses will flock to whichever side they think will win,
他们向来如此
as they always have.
还有其他的消息
There's other news.
从渊凯来的
From Yunkai.
没有了无垢者来巩固您的统治
Without the Unsullied to enforce your rule,
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
贤主大人们重新控制了城市
the Wise Masters have retaken control of the city.
他们重新奴役了留在那里的自由人
They've reenslaved the freedmen who stayed behind
并且发誓要向您复仇
and sworn to take revenge against you.
还有 在阿斯塔波
And in Astapor,
由您任命统治城市的议会
the council you installed to rule over the city
被一个叫克莱昂的屠夫推翻了
has been overthrown by a butcher named Cleon
他还以“伟大的国王”自居
who's declared himself "His Imperial Majesty."
你们退下吧
Please leave me.
你留下 乔拉
Not you, Jorah.
似乎我解放奴隶湾的行动
It appears my liberation of Slaver's Bay
进行得并不顺利
isn't going quite as planned.
您可以把这一切都抛之脑后
You could sail for Westeros
直接驶向维斯特洛
and leave it all behind.
现在坐在铁王座上的只是个男孩
A boy sits on the Iron Throne.
而且很多人认为他是私生子 根本不配继位
A boy many believe to be a bastard with no right to it.
这正是敌人最脆弱之时
They've never been more vulnerable.
在魁尔斯你曾劝阻我不要急躁
You counseled me against rashness once in Qarth.
我没听
I didn't listen.
后来一切都顺利
That all worked out well.
如果我连奴隶湾都无法控制
How can I rule seven kingdoms
又该如何统治七大王国？
if I can't control Slaver's Bay?
人们有什么理由信任我？
Why should anyone trust me?
人们有什么理由追随我？
Why should anyone follow me?
您是坦格利安后裔
You're a Targaryen.
您是龙之母
You're the Mother of Dragons.
这还不够
I need to be more than that.
我不会让那些被我解放的人重新戴上镣铐
I will not let those I have freed slide back into chains.
我不去维斯特洛了
I will not sail for Westeros.
那您要做什么？
What, then?
我要做女王该做的事情
I will do what queens do.
我要统治这里
I will rule.
珊莎·史塔克
小恶魔的妻子
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头” 赫伦堡公爵
戴上兜帽
Pull up your hood.
背影足够他们记住了
A memorable shade.
但他们怎么认出我是谁？
But how would they know?
你知道穷人最喜欢听什么故事吗？
You know what kind of stories poor men enjoy the most?
是那些他们永远无缘得见的富家女的故事
Ones about rich girls they'll never meet.
去鹰巢城只有这条路吗？
Is this the only way into the Eyrie?
这山是无法穿越的
The mountains are impassable.
想要抵达鹰巢城
If you want to get to the Eyrie,
只能通过血门
you need to go through the Bloody Gate.
无论你有多少军队
It doesn't matter how large your army is,
想要攻打血门 你就得走这条路
if you attack this gate, you do it on this road,
三人并排
three men abreast
然后像山羊一样被宰掉
and get slaughtered like goats.
谷地最早的领主们并没有什么财富
The first Lords of the Vale didn't have much,
但他们拥有这些山
but they had these mountains
而且他们懂得物尽其用
and they knew how to use them.
他们在这里建造的城堡从未被攻陷过
And the fortress they built here has never been overcome.
一千年来一次也没有
Not once in 1,000 years.
了解自己的优势 合理发挥优势
Know your strengths, use them wisely,
就能以一敌万
and one man can be worth 10,000.
是谁要通过血门？
Who would pass the Bloody Gate?
培提尔·贝里席公爵和他的侄女阿莲
Lord Petyr Baelish and his niece Alayne.
唐纳尔·韦伍德
血门骑士
敬礼
Stand to.
- 敬礼！  - 敬礼!
- Stand to! - Stand to!
欢迎回来 培提尔大人
Welcome back, Lord Baelish.
莱莎·徒利
凯特琳·徒利的妹妹
琼恩·艾琳的遗孀
劳勃·艾琳
“乖罗宾” 鹰巢城公爵
琼恩·艾琳独子
培提尔叔叔！
Uncle Petyr!
大人
My lord.
我有个小礼物送给你
I have brought you a gift.
贝里席大人
Lord Baelish.
- 夫人  - 你看培提尔叔叔给我带了什么
- My lady. - Look what Uncle Petyr brought me.
漂亮的礼物 送给可爱的男孩
A beautiful gift for a beautiful boy.
很荣幸见到您 艾林夫人
It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance, Lady Arryn.
我的名字是阿——
My name is Al--
哦 把兜帽摘下来吧 孩子
Oh, do take down that hood, child.
你不觉得我早已知晓你的身份吗？
Don't you think I know who you are?
你以为我会让我的未婚夫
You think I'd let my intended
因为紧急事务离开鹰巢城
leave the Eyrie on urgent business
而我却不知道所为何事？
without knowing what that business was?
我放他离开 他才能把你带来我这儿
I let him go so he could bring you here to me.
你我血脉相连
My flesh and blood.
见到您真是太好了 莱莎姨妈
It's wonderful to meet you, Aunt Lysa.
在其他人面前千万不能这样叫我
You mustn't call me that in front of anyone else.
当然 我明白
Of course. I understand.
不能让任何人知道你在这里
No one can know you're here.
否则我们的处境将非常危险
It would put us in a very precarious position.
我一个字也不会透露的
I would never say a thing.
多年以来
The Lannisters want to destroy us.
兰尼斯特家族一直在试图摧毁我们
They've been trying for years.
结果现在他们倒尝到了被摧毁的滋味
Now they know what it feels like.
妈妈说 他们杀了你妈妈还砍了你哥哥的脑袋
Mummy said they killed your mother and they chopped off your brother's head.
没错 还砍了我父亲的头
They did, and my father's.
他们也杀了我父亲 用毒药
They killed my father, too, with poison.
我想让那个兰尼斯特小矮子飞
I wanted to make the little Lannister baby man fly,
但妈妈不让我这么做
but Mother said I couldn't.
让他飞？
Make him fly?
从月门飞
Through the Moon Door.
更重要的是
And on top of everything else,
他们还硬要你嫁给那个下流的侏儒
they made you marry that filthy troll.
是的 其实我俩都是被迫的
They did. They made us both.
提利昂大人也不情愿
Lord Tyrion didn't want to.
这我一点儿都不信
I don't believe that for a moment.
他有没有强上了你？
Did he force himself on you?
没有
No.
- 我们从没——  - 那就好
- We never--  Good.
罗宾 她是你的表姐 珊莎
Robin, this is your cousin Sansa.
但在其他人面前 你不能叫她珊莎
But you're not to call her Sansa in front of anyone
只有在我和培提尔叔叔面前才行 懂了吗
but Uncle Petyr and myself. Do you understand?
珊莎 这是我的儿子罗宾
Sansa, this is my son Robin.
很高兴见到你 罗宾
It's a pleasure to meet you, Robin.
罗宾 带珊莎去她的寝室
Robin, show Sansa to her chamber.
走后楼梯
Take the back stairs.
去吧 我们待会聊
Go. We'll speak soon.
你怎么耽误了这么久？
What took you so long?
忙着安排托曼一世继位
Arranging for the ascension of King Tommen I,
救出珊莎 还有把她安全送到这儿
extricating Sansa, getting her here alive.
她已经安全抵达了 今晚在她身上花的时间已经太多了
She's here. We've spent more than enough time on her for one evening.
我们今晚成婚吧
Let's get married tonight.
这样的喜事...
Ought we not...
我们不该先通知谷地的领主们吗
inform the Lords of the Vale about the ceremony?
谷地只有一个领主
There's only one Lord of the Vale.
其他人统统去死吧
The others can all hang.
一个个趴在楼梯上像秃鹫一样笑脸迎合
Lurking and simpering on the stairs like buzzards
我丈夫一死 他们就开始觊觎着我
the moment my husband died, trying to get their claws in me.
我认为我们得等……
I do think that we could wait until--
我等够了 培提尔
I'm done waiting, Petyr.
我们多年前就早已有过婚姻之实了
We had our wedding night many years ago.
你不记得了吗？
Or don't you remember?
清晰如昨日
Like it was yesterday.
什么样的妻子会像我那般待你？
What wife would do for you the things I've done for you?
什么样的妻子会像我那般信任你？
What wife would trust you the way I've trusted you?
当你给我那剂毒药
When you gave me those drops
让我下在琼恩的酒里
and told me to pour them into Jon's wine,
我丈夫的酒里时--
my husband's wine--
当你让我写信给凯特
when you told me to write a letter to Cat
告诉她是兰尼斯特--
telling her it was the Lannisters--
往事已成过去
The deed is done.
随风而逝
Faded into nothing.
若不提及 便非真相
Only speaking of it can make it real.
那就今晚吧
Tonight it is, then.
让我先为婚礼沐浴更衣吧
Let me bathe and dress for the occasion.
等我准备好 就去召修士来
Once I'm presentable, I'll call on the septon immediately.
事先警告你
I'm warning you.
我和我丈夫在床上可是要叫出来的
I'm going to scream when my husband makes love to me.
我要大声的叫
I'm going to scream so loud,
叫声要传到狭海对岸
they'll hear me clear across the Narrow Sea.
你打算何时举行婚礼？
When will the wedding take place in your mind?
什么时候合适都行
As soon as decency permits.
要先给托曼足够的时间哀悼他的哥哥
After we've allowed Tommen the appropriate time to mourn his brother
玛格丽也要哀悼她的丈夫
and Margaery to mourn her husband.
- 两周？ - 我觉得合理
- A fortnight? - That seems reasonable.
不要杂耍 不要侏儒比武
No jugglers, no jousting dwarves,
也不要七十七道菜
no 77-course meals.
那你什么时候嫁给洛拉斯？
And your wedding to Loras?
托曼成婚不久后
Shortly after Tommen's.
- 不久后？ - 两周后
- Shortly? - A fortnight.
我知道你不喜欢他们
I know you don't like them.
我之前也不喜欢你丈夫
I didn't like your husband.
他以前总爱拍我的背
Used to pat me on the back a lot.
我不信任他
I didn't trust him.
这点我们倒是一样
We had that in common.
我们与人结盟 但没必要信任他们
You don't need to make formal alliances with people you trust.
那可以信任谁？
Then whom can we trust?
只有我们自己
Ourselves alone.
提利尔
The Tyrells
是唯一可以在资源上
are our only true rivals
与我们抗衡的家族
in terms of resources
而我们需要他们的支持
and we need them on our side.
劳勃是不怎么有钱
Robert wasn't particularly rich.
劳勃有我们的资助
Robert had me funding him.
战争开销如流水
Wars swallow gold like a pit in the earth.
所以我们之前才能大获全胜
I suppose that explains why we did so well in the last one.
你知道去年西境总共开采了多少金矿吗？
Do you know how much gold was mined in the Westerlands this past year?
不知道
Haven't a clue.
来 猜猜看
Go on, your best guess.
磅 吨 还是盎司？
Pounds, tons, ounces?
不管什么单位 答案都是一样
Doesn't matter. The answer is the same.
这不可能
That can't be.
我们的最后一个金矿三年前就空了
Our last working mine ran dry three years ago.
那我们怎么应付的开销？
Then how do we pay for anything?
王座欠着铁金库的债
The crown owes the Iron Bank of Braavos
一笔巨债
a tremendous amount of money.
多少？
How much?
很大一笔
A tremendous amount.
铁金库肯定有好说话的人
There must be someone at the Iron Bank
你跟他通融通融
you can speak to, come to some arrangement.
铁金库就是铁金库
The Iron Bank is the Iron Bank.
没有什么 好说话的人
There is no someone.
那也是有人干活的地方 是由人组成的机构
Someone does work there. It is comprised of people.
一座神庙还是一块块石头组成的呢
And a temple is comprised of stones.
一块石头碎了 大不了另一块补上
One stone crumbles and another takes its place.
神庙照样能屹立千年不倒
And the temple holds its form for 1,000 years or more.
铁金库就是这样一座神庙
That's what the Iron Bank is-- a temple.
我们都活在它的阴影下却不自知
We all live in its shadow and almost none of us know it.
你无法逃离他们 无法欺骗他们
You can't run from them. You can't cheat them.
你不能拿借口来搪塞
You can't sway them with excuses.
如果你欠他们钱 还想活命的话
If you owe them money and you don't want to crumble yourself,
就乖乖还钱
you pay it back.
把提利尔笼络在朝廷里
Vesting the Tyrells in the crown
在这方面对我们有利
will help a great deal in this respect.
都是为了家族利益 我明白
It's for the good of the family, I understand that.
但我的兄弟们未必明白
I'm not sure my brothers do.
我知道你心里认定提利昂有罪
I know you're building a strong case against Tyrion.
作为母亲 你有权这么做
And as a mother, that is your right.
但我作为法官 我不能与你讨论审判
But as a judge, I cannot discuss the trial with you.
我表示尊重
I respect that.
我们没必要讨论
We don't need to discuss it.
没什么比兰尼斯特家族的传承更重要
The Lannister legacy is the only thing that matters.
为了保护家族 你发动了一场战争
You've started wars to protect this family.
詹姆不愿继承家业
Turned your back on Jaime
你已与他决裂
for refusing to contribute to its future.
提利昂亲手将家族的未来付之一炬
What does Tyrion deserve
又该付出什么样的代价？
for lighting that future on fire?
乔佛里
Joffrey.
瑟曦
Cersei.
瓦德·佛雷
Walder Frey.
艾丽娅·史塔克
马林·特兰
Meryn Trant.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
泰温·兰尼斯特
Tywin Lannister.
红袍女
The Red Woman.
贝里·唐德利恩
Beric Dondarrion.
密尔的索罗斯
Thoros of Myr.
伊林·派恩
Ilyn Payne.
魔山
The Mountain.
能不能闭嘴
Would you shut up?
我不念一遍这些名字就睡不着
I can't sleep until I say the names.
念遍每个维斯特洛人的鸟名字么
The names of every fucking person in Westeros?
只有那些我要杀的人
Only the ones I'm going to kill.
仇恨可是支撑人活下去的好东西
Hate's as good a thing as any to keep a person going.
比其他玩意儿强多了
Better than most.
等碰上我哥哥
We come across my brother,
也许我们都能在自己的名单上划掉一个人
maybe we can both cross a name off our list.
要是他现在就在这 你要怎么做？
If he were here right now, what would you do?
我会让他闭上臭嘴
I'd tell him to shut the fuck up
让我好好睡觉
so I can get some sleep.
快点 把它念完得了
Go on, get it over with,
你那个杀人名单
your list of doomed men.
就快念完了
I'm almost done.
只差一个
Only one name left.
继续啊
Go on.
猎狗
The Hound.
谢谢
Thank you.
你妈妈一直喜欢甜食 知道吗？
Your mother always had a sweet tooth, you know?
- 是嘛？ - 哦 那可不
- Really? - Oh, yes.
晚饭时 她都是直奔蜂蜜蛋糕
At suppertime, she would go straight for honey cakes,
还有蜜饯杏仁 奶油蛋羹
candied almonds, custard.
所有甜食
Anything sweet.
最后你外公
Eventually, your grandfather
不得不派个修女吃饭时监督她
had to assign a septa to watch her at meals.
毕竟凯特是长女
Cat was the firstborn daughter after all.
只有保持魅力
It was important that she remain desirable
父亲才能为她安排一门好亲事
so Father could arrange a good match for her
她却开始长胖
and she was starting to get fat.
我母亲长胖？
My mother fat?
她从来不准我
She never let me have my pudding
在晚饭前吃布丁
until I'd finished all my proper food.
我说的是她嫁给你爸去北境之前的事
This is before she married your father and moved to the North.
到你出生时 你父亲的简朴作风已经把她传染了
By the time you were born, your father's austerity had become hers.
婚姻能改变人
Marriage changes people.
我不是让你停下
I didn't mean for you to stop.
继续吃 好好吃
Go on, enjoy them.
好吃吗？
How do you like them?
很美味
They're delicious.
哪里来的柠檬？这里这么高肯定种不了
Where did you get the lemons? You can't grow them up here.
哦 当然种不了
Oh, gods, no.
培提尔从君临千里迢迢带来整整三箱
Petyr had three crates brought all the way from King's Landing.
他知道你喜欢吃柠檬蛋糕
He knew you liked lemon cakes.
他人真好
He's so kind.
他非常关心你
He really cares for you.
想想若不是他 你会在哪儿
Think where you'd be without him.
落入他们手中 因谋杀罪受审
In their clutches and tried for murder.
是的 我非常幸运
Yes. I'm very lucky.
他对你有一种责任感
He feels responsible for you.
哦 我知道 我非常感激
Oh, I know he does. I'm so grateful.
为什么？
Why?
为什么他觉得要对你负责？
Why does he feel responsible for you?
呃 我是半个徒利
Well, I'm half Tully.
- 他非常爱您的家族 - 他爱的是你妈
- He loved your family so much. - Loved your mother.
- 不 - 这才是你想说的
- No. - That's what you wanted to say.
他爱你 莱莎阿姨 他跟你结婚了
He loves you, Aunt Lysa. He's married to you.
你母亲从来没有爱过他 从来没有
Your mother never loved him. Never.
凯特总是直奔最甜美的猎物
Cat always went straight for the sweetest thing.
最明显的目标 比如你大伯布兰登
The most obvious thing. Your Uncle Brandon.
你那英俊 傲慢 残忍的大伯布兰登
Your handsome, arrogant, cruel Uncle Brandon.
他在决斗中差点杀了培提尔
He almost killed Petyr in a duel.
你妈却对他死心塌地
And your mother loved him anyway.
你妈对培提尔
And now Petyr is risking his life to save you,
还比不上他养的那帮妓女
the daughter of a woman who didn't love him
培提尔却舍命救你
no more than those whores in his brothels.
- 他跟你说过那些妓女么？ - 没有
- Has he told you about them? - No.
他没告诉过你 她们都用身体做什么可耻的事情？
He hasn't told you about the vile things they do with their bodies?
用身体让他做那些可耻的事情？
The vile things they let him do with their bodies?
- 不 从没有 - 你怀孕了么？
-  No, never. - Are you pregnant?
什么？不 我说过 提利昂大人和我从未——
What? No, I told you. Lord Tyrion and I never--
我不是在问提利昂
I wasn't asking about Tyrion.
你让培提尔对你的身体做过什么？
What have you let Petyr do with your body?
- 莱莎阿姨 没有 我—— - 你这年轻的 美丽的身体
- Aunt Lysa, no, I-- - Your young, pretty body.
- 什么也没有 我还是处女 - 别对我撒谎
- Nothing. I'm a virgin. - Don't lie to me.
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me.
你骗不了我
I'll know if you lie.
我还是处女 我发誓
I'm a virgin, I swear it.
他爱你 莱莎阿姨
He loves you, Aunt Lysa.
他只说过我是个笨女孩
All he says is that I'm stupid.
我是个有着愚蠢梦想的笨女孩
I'm a stupid little girl with stupid dreams
永远也不会吸取教训 还有我是个糟糕的骗子
who never learns and I'm a terrible liar,
所以我应该永远说真话
so I should always tell the truth.
我向您发誓他从来没有碰过我
And I swear to you that he has never touched me.
- 一次也没有 从来没有 - 嘘 嘘 嘘
- Not once, not ever. - Shh. Shh. Shh.
没事了
It's all right.
一切都会好的
It will all be all right.
你很快就会成为一个寡妇
You'll be a widow soon.
他们会以弑君罪处决那个侏儒
They'll execute that dwarf for murdering the king
到时你就可以嫁给罗宾了
and you'll be free to marry Robin.
你就会成为谷地公爵夫人
You'll be the Lady of the Vale.
嗯
Hmm.
布蕾妮·塔斯
“美人”
波德瑞克·派恩
布蕾妮的侍从
你没学过骑马么？
Didn't they teach you how to ride a horse?
小时候学过 小姐
Yes, my lady, when I was young.
不过在提利昂大人身边并不怎么需要骑马
There wasn't much call for it with Lord Tyrion, though.
他喜欢坐轿子
He preferred litters.
也许你应该跟他呆在一起
Perhaps you should have stayed with him.
我的行程对你来说不会太舒服
It's not going to be a pleasant journey for you.
天气不好的话 可能要好几周才能到达长城
It could take weeks to get to the Wall, depending on the weather.
路可真远啊
That's a long way off.
珊莎小姐的哥哥在黑城堡
Well, Lady Sansa's brother's at Castle Black.
如果我是她 我就会去那儿
If I were her, that's where I'd go.
你随时都可以停下来
Feel free to stop at any point.
绝不 小姐 我是你的侍从
Never, my lady. I'm your squire.
这么久以来 我身边都没有侍从
I've made it this far in the world without a squire.
我不觉得我现在需要一个
I don't see why I need one now.
所有的骑士都有侍从 小姐
All knights have squires, my lady.
我不是个骑士
I'm not a knight.
我也不是个奴隶主 你不是我的财产
And I'm not a slaver, either. I don't own you.
我立过誓了 小姐
I swore an oath, my lady.
我现在解除你的誓言
I am releasing you from that oath.
也就是说你可以走了
That means you could leave.
我知道
I know.
你觉得如果你走了会发生什么？
What do you think will happen if you leave?
他们会说我不是个很好的侍从
They'll say I wasn't a very good squire.
- 你在搞什么鬼？ - 练习
- The hell you doing? - Practicing.
- 练什么 怎么去死么？ - 没有人能杀我
- What, ways to die? - No one's going to kill me.
你要这样扭来扭去就死定了
They will if you nance around like that.
架可不是这么打的
That's no way to fight.
这不是打架 这是水之舞
It's not fighting. It's water dancing.
跳舞？
Dancing?
也许你应该穿条裙子
Maybe you ought to put on a dress.
谁教给你这玩意儿的？
Who taught you that shite?
有史以来最伟大的剑客
The greatest swordsman who ever lived.
西利欧·佛瑞尔 布拉佛斯海王的首席剑士
Syrio Forel, the First Sword to the Sealord of Braavos.
布拉佛斯
Braavos.
是个头发油乎乎的杂种 我敢打赌
Greasy-haired little bastard, I bet.
他们都一样
They all are.
你以为你什么都知道么？
What do you know about anything?
我打赌他的头发比乔佛里的屄还油
I bet his hair is greasier than Joffrey's cunt.
- 才不是 - 呵 他还活着么？
- It was not. - Was? He dead?
- 他死了 - 怎么死的？
- Yes. - How?
- 被人杀死的 - 谁呢？
- He was killed. - Who by?
马林·特兰 所以马林爵士才——
Meryn Trant. That's why Ser Meryn--
马林·特兰？
Meryn Trant?
有史以来最伟大的剑客被马林·他妈的·特兰杀死了？
The greatest swordsman who ever lived killed by Meryn fucking Trant?
- 他寡不敌众 - 随便哪个男妓只要有把剑
- He was outnumbered. - Any boy whore with a sword
就能打败三个马林·特兰
could beat three Meryn Trants.
西利欧没有剑 也没有盔甲 只有一根木棍
Syrio didn't have a sword. Or armor. Just a stick.
有史以来最伟大的剑客没有剑？
The greatest swordsman who ever lived didn't have a sword?
好吧 你有一把剑
All right. You have a sword.
我们来看看他教了你些什么
Let's see what he taught you.
来吧 为了你的布拉佛斯朋友
Go on, do it for your Braavosi friend.
像你的其他朋友一样 都死了
Dead like all the rest of your friends.
你的朋友死了 而不是马林·特兰
Your friend's dead and Meryn Trant's not
因为特兰穿着盔甲
'cause Trant had armor
还他妈有一把大剑
and a big fucking sword.
奥柏伦·马泰尔
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
陛下
Your Grace.
奥柏伦亲王 在写信？
Prince Oberyn. Writing letters?
实际上是一首诗
A poem, actually.
我可以带您游览花园么？
May I show you the gardens?
我想我不能拒绝王室的邀请
I couldn't very well refuse a royal escort.
确实如此
No, you couldn't.
我还不知道你是个诗人
I didn't realize you were a poet.
水平一般
Not a very good one.
写给你的情人的？
For your paramour?
写给我其中一个女儿
For one of my daughters.
你有不少女儿 是吗？
You have several, don't you?
八个
Eight.
八个？
Eight?
八个女儿？
Eight daughters?
第五个女儿不好相处
The fifth is difficult.
我用我姐姐的名字伊莉亚给她命名
I named her after my sister Elia.
美丽的名字
Beautiful name.
是啊
Yes.
但我没法在提到这名字时不感到悲伤
But I can't say it without turning sad.
而在悲伤之后
And after I turn sad,
我会变得愤怒
I grow angry.
也许这就是她不好相处的原因
Perhaps that's why she's difficult.
诸神喜欢他们愚蠢的玩笑 不是么？
The gods love their stupid jokes, don't they?
哪个玩笑？
Which joke is that?
你是多恩的亲王
You're a prince of Dorne.
一个传奇的战士
A legendary fighter.
一个全维斯特洛都害怕的人
A brilliant man feared throughout Westeros.
但你救不了你的姐姐
But you could not save your sister.
我出自兰尼斯特家族 当了十九年的王后
I'm a Lannister. Queen for 19 years.
是世上最有权势的人的女儿
Daughter of the most powerful man alive.
但我救不了我的儿子
But I could not save my son.
权力又有什么好处
What good is power
如果连自己最爱的人都保护不了？
if you cannot protect the ones you love?
我们可以复仇
We can avenge them.
是的 我们可以复仇
Yes, we can avenge them.
你真的相信提利昂谋杀了你的儿子？
You really believe Tyrion murdered your son?
我知道是他
I know he did.
我们会举行一场审判并会找出真相
We will have a trial and we will learn the truth.
至少 我们会有一场审判
We'll have a trial, anyway.
我有一年多没看到我的女儿了
I haven't seen my daughter in over a year.
上次我看到她时
The last time I saw her,
她和两个我的女儿在流水花园中游泳
she was swimming with two of my girls in the Water Gardens.
在阳光下欢笑
Laughing in the sun.
我希望是真的
I want to believe that.
我希望她过得快乐
I want to believe she's happy.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我们多恩不会伤害小女孩
We don't hurt little girls in Dorne.
世上所有地方 人们都会伤害小女孩
Everywhere in the world, they hurt little girls.
你可以替我带一件礼物给她吗？
Would you bring her a gift for me?
我没赶上她的命名日
I wasn't there for her name day.
也不知道什么时候才能再见到她
I don't know when I'll see her again.
当然
Anything at all.
君临城最好的造船工
The best shipwrights in King's Landing
已经工作了好几个月来造那艘船
have been working on it for months.
弥赛菈喜欢开阔的水面
Myrcella loves the open water.
我会把这船开去阳戟城送给她
I will have it sailed down to Sunspear for her.
请告诉她……
Please tell her...
她的母亲非常想她
her mother misses her very much.
哦 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
见鬼
Hells.
神啊
Gods.
你把皮剥了么？
Did you remove the skin?
没有 小姐
No, my lady.
你以前烤过兔子么？
Have you ever cooked a rabbit before?
没有 小姐
No, my lady.
你以前为提利昂大人煮过任何东西么？
Did you ever cook anything for Lord Tyrion?
没有 小姐
No, my lady.
都是厨师做的
That was the cooks.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我帮你卸下盔甲
I'm helping you with your armor.
我一直都自己卸盔甲 非常感谢
I've been removing my own armor for quite some time, thank you very much.
你到底都给提利昂大人做些什么事？
What exactly did you do for Lord Tyrion?
我伺候他用餐 饭后清理餐桌
I brought him his meals and cleared his table when he was finished.
浆洗衣物
I kept his clothing and linens clean.
为他送信 转达回复
Carried his messages and returned the replies.
多数时间都在倒酒
Mostly I poured wine.
哈
Oh.
你侍奉提利昂大人那会儿
Whilst in Lord Tyrion's service,
有没有在战场上做过点什么？
did you ever do anything remotely related to combat?
我杀过一个人
I killed a man.
什么人？
Who?
一个御林铁卫
A Kingsguard.
在黑水河上 他要杀提利昂大人
He tried to kill Lord Tyrion at the Blackwater.
你怎么能杀掉一个御林铁卫？
How did you kill a Kingsguard?
我用枪戳进他的后脑
I pushed a spear through the back of his head.
真他妈烦
Bloody ridiculous.
给我松开带子
Help me with these straps.
洛克
卢斯·波顿的副官
嘿
Hey.
嘿 起来
Hey, get up.
起来
Get up.
小子 就是那个 扔进去
That's it lad, put it inside.
把火重新生起来 冻死了
Get the fire going again. We're all freezing.
对 咱们还缺个妞儿
Aye. What we need is a girl there.
我得撒泡尿
I've got to have a piss.
给我闭嘴
Now keep quiet.
布兰·史塔克
易形者
阿多
临冬城的马僮
梅拉·黎德
布兰·史塔克的保护者
玖健·黎德
拥有绿之视野的男孩
你得喝点水
You need water.
不要紧
It doesn't matter.
谁说不要紧
Of course it matters.
没什么能困住你
You mustn't let anything stop you.
他们已经困住我了
They already have stopped me.
不
No.
你不在这里
You're not here.
你在千里之外
You're far from here.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
在那座山上
At the hill.
有棵巨大的鱼梁木
A great weirwood tree.
你也看到了
You've seen it, too.
梅拉和我 连同阿多
Meera and I, even Hodor,
我们只是为你带路
we're only here to guide you.
他在等你
He's waiting for you.
我们必须找到它
We have to find it.
你必须找到它
You have to make it.
我们会的
We will.
这——这不是结局
This-- this isn't the end.
不是你的结局
Not for you.
还不是
Not yet.
我们……
How...
怎么能知道结局如何？
will we know the end?
你会知道的
You'll know.
弟兄们
Brothers.
没听见你的动静
You do move quiet.
- 有多少人？ - 11个
- How many? - 11 men.
多数都醉醺醺的
Most of them already drunk.
没人望风 好像他们什么都不在乎
No guards posted. They don't seem to have a care in the world.
剁翻他们就跟切馅饼一样
We'll carve them up like walnut pie.
卡尔是跳蚤窝的一流杀手
Karl was a top paid cutthroat in Flea Bottom.
葛兰
“笨牛” 守夜人游骑兵
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
我见过他使刀的本事
I've seen what he can do with a knife.
你见过我使刀的本事么？
Have you seen what I can do with a knife?
还没
Not yet.
堡垒西面有个小棚子 咱们先把那儿占了
There's a hut on the west side of the keep. We should steer clear of it.
为什么？
Why?
他们在那栓了些猎狗
They've got some hounds chained up inside.
没了狗闻气味 咱们可以摸得更近
Closer we can get without the dogs sniffing us, the better.
今晚是新月
New moon tonight.
休息一会
Get some rest.
天黑动手
We move at sundown.
我喜欢卷发妹子
I've always liked a girl with curls.
卡尔·坦纳
守夜人叛徒
有品位
A touch of class.
我完事了你们上
You take whatever's left.
吊起来
Get her up.
住手
Stop.
停下 你们要干嘛？
Stop. What are you doing?
阿多 阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor. Hodor.
住手 住手！
Stop. Stop!
- 阿多 阿多 - 停手！
- Hodor. Hodor. - Stop!
- 求你们了 - 阿多
- Please. -  Hodor.
- 求你们放开她！ - 阿多 阿多
- Please, get off her! - Hodor. Hodor.
求你们了！求你们放开她！
Please! Please, leave her alone!
求你们停手 停手
Please, stop. Stop.
- 你们要干吗？放开她！- 阿多 阿多
-  What are you doing? Leave her alone! -  Hodor. Hodor.
- 不！- 嘘
-  No! - Shh.
嘘 嘘 嘘
Shh, shh, shh.
嘘
Shh.
头发挺漂亮 哈？
You've got pretty hair, don't you?
你这样的漂亮贵族小姐
Now what is a pretty little highborn girl like you
到这阴森的林子里来做什么 嗯？
doing out here in the deep, dark woods, eh?
你不躲在老爸的城堡里 偏想找刺激是吗？
You left your daddy's castle looking for trouble, didn't you?
你不想穿裙子
No dresses for you.
想要粗野一点
You like it rough, don't you?
想要跟贱民搞 是吗？
You like it in the gutter, don't you?
如果你放了我姐姐 我可以帮你
If you let my sister go, I can help you.
你可以帮我？
You can help me?
是的
I can.
你怎么帮我？
And how you gonna do that?
我有绿之视野 我能看到事情
I have the sight. I can see things.
真是帮了大忙
That's very helpful.
那些还未发生的事情
Things that haven't happened yet.
有点意思
What a fine thing.
有意思
A fine thing.
你看到我要对你姐姐做的事了吗？
Have you seen what I'm gonna do to your sister?
你看到他们要对你姐姐做的事了吗？
Have you seen what they're going to do to your sister?
没有
No.
睁大眼
Don't close your eyes.
我看到你死在今晚
I saw you die tonight.
我看到你的尸体在燃烧
I saw your body burn.
我看到雪花落下 掩埋你的尸骨
I saw the snow fall and bury your bones.
快拿兵器！
To arms!
他们来了 守夜人来了
They're here, the Night's Watch.
各位 欢迎参加营救晚会
Rescue party is here, lads.
小姐
Lady.
- 琼恩也在？ - 没错
- Is Jon with you? - Aye.
我带你见他
I'll take you to him.
你就是布兰登·史塔克？
You're Brandon Stark?
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
小瘸子大人 我们可得骑好一阵 小子
The little crippled lord. We're going for a ride, boy.
琼恩！琼恩！
Jon! Jon!
再嚷嚷我就切了他们的喉咙
Keep talking and I'll cut your friends' throats.
先从这傻大个开始 听见没？
Starting with the idiot. Do you hear?
听见没？
Do you hear?
阿多！阿多！
Hodor! Hodor!
阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor.
阿多 阿多 阿多
Hodor. Hodor. Hodor.
阿多
Hodor.
阿多 拿他的刀 给我松绑
Hodor, get his knife. Cut me loose.
- 阿多 拿他的刀 - 阿多
-  Hodor, get his knife. - Hodor.
给我松绑 阿多
Cut me loose, Hodor.
去救玖健和梅拉
Jojen and Meera, free them.
快去！
Go!
琼恩
Jon.
琼恩！
Jon!
他要是看到你 就不会放你往北走
If he sees you, he won't let you go north.
- 他是我哥哥 - 他想保护你
- He's my brother. - And wants to protect you.
他会带你回黑城堡
He'll take you back to Castle Black.
你得做个决断
You have to decide.
想不想找到三眼乌鸦？
Do you want to find the three-eyed raven?
- 阿多 - 阿多
- Hodor. - Hodor.
你得救出夏天
We need to free Summer.
然后我们就得走了
And we need to go.
雪诺大人
Lord Snow.
你要带我回去审判吗？
Are you bringing me back for trial?
我们在这过得很爽
We had a good thing here.
我们是自由人
We were free men.
你们永远得不到自由
You'll never be free.
你们永远不知道自由的感觉
You'll never know what that's like.
你在城堡里学的剑法 嗯？
You learn how to fight in a castle?
有老教头教你怎么站位
Some old man teach you how to stand,
怎么闪避
how to parry?
教你怎么战斗不失荣誉
How to fight with honor?
你知道荣誉错在哪么？
You know what's wrong with honor?
你
You.
没事吧？
Are you all right?
跟我来
Come with me.
来
Come on.
我们死了四个弟兄？
We lost four brothers?
五个
Five.
什么狗屁东西才能做出这样的事来？
What the seven hells could do that to a man?
我数出了10个叛徒
I count 10 dead mutineers.
洛克说有11个
Locke said there were 11 of them.
雷斯特哪去了？
Where's Rast?
雷斯特
守夜人叛徒
- 第十一个 - 琼恩
- Here's another. - Jon.
我的天呐
Where in seven hells?
过来
Come here.
白灵
琼恩·雪诺的冰原狼
我好想你啊 伙计
I missed you, boy.
她们怎么办？
What should we do with this lot?
你们在这里不安全
It's not safe for you here on your own.
曼斯·雷德的军队正往这来
Mance Rayder has an army heading this way
还有比曼斯更可怕的东西
and there's worse out there than Mance.
跟我们回黑城堡吧
Come with us to Castle Black.
我们可以给你们些活干 保护你们
We can find you work. Keep you safe.
乌鸦大人 好意我们心领了
Meaning all respect, Ser Crow,
卡斯特比那些东西还要可怕
Craster beat us and worse.
你的乌鸦弟兄们比卡斯特更可怕
Your brother crows beat us and worse.
我们会自己活下去的
We'll find our own way.
你们要留在这？
You want to stay here
留在卡斯特的堡垒？
in Craster's Keep?
烧掉它
Burn it to the ground
连同死尸一起烧掉
and all the dead with it.
衣柜字幕组出品